別に観に行かなくてもいいｱﾙよ｡
ﾃﾒｴら
それでも銀魂ついてんのか！
銀さん！
しかと その目ん玉に焼きつけな！
いつから違った｡ ｵﾚたちの道は｡
(神楽)中身もﾃﾚﾋﾞの
再放送みたいなもんだから➡
ｵﾚはただ壊すだけだ｡
この腐った世界を｡
(新八)わ～っ！ まるで
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ映画のCMみたいですね！
宇宙にはまだ
おもしろそうな連中がいるんだね｡
おい～！
って ﾎﾞｸ予告に映ってねえ！
ﾃﾒｴの言う余計なもんが
どれだけの力を持ってるか➡
(銀時)でも どうせ１年後には
ﾚﾝﾀﾙ屋に並ぶんだろ｡
＜歴史とは強者の弁である｡
History is written by the victors.
だが 天空に輝く日の光が
小さな星々の輝きをかき消し➡
But even if the radiant sunlight hides
the lights of the smaller stars,
even if those lights never
reach the people,
人々の目に届かぬとも➡
そこには己が命をかけ
輝き続けた星々が存在する｡
there exists a star, who risks
its life to shine brightly.
これは そんな星の物語である＞
This is a story about one such star.
Quitting the business to
live in retirement, eh?
《足を洗って隠居生活か｡
Not bad.
それも悪くない｡
But I wouldn't be able to stand
such a backwards place.
だが ｵﾚだったら
こんな さびれたところ➡
ご免こうむるがな》
["NAGAI"]
(永井)記者風情が今さら
わしになんの用じゃい｡
What would a reporter
want with me now?
いえね ちょっと
お話を伺えないかと｡
Well, I was hoping to talk a bit.
言わずもがなかもしれませんが➡
I shouldn't need to tell you that I'm
researching the Anti-Foreigner War.
今 私
攘夷戦争について調べてましてね｡
ぜひあなたに教えていただきたい｡
I would love to hear
あの戦争を従軍記者として➡
your perspective as a military reporter
天人 幕府 攘夷志士｡
who was embedded with the Amanto, Bakufu,
and the Anti-Foreigner Faction during the war
それぞれの視線で見
いくつもの戦いに従軍し➡
and saw many different sights while
surviving many perilous situations.
いくつもの死線を
乗り越えてきたあなたに｡
わしは 何も｡
I saw nothing...
いやあなたなら知ってるはずです｡
永井さん！
No, you would know, Nagai-san!
攘夷戦争を取材するなかで必ず
ぶち当たる 謎の人物のことを｡
As a journalist during the Anti-Foreigner War,
you must have encountered that enigmatic figure...
伝聞だけが一人歩きし
今や伝説上の人物とも言われる➡
Only rumors remain...
Now considered a myth...
あの男のことを｡
You would know about that man...
帰れと言っても
素直に帰るﾀﾏでもなさそうじゃな｡
You're not one to leave even
if I told you to, are you?
["It's better to take care of this year's business within the year, but once the year is about to end, you figure that you might as well put it off till next year for a fresh start. That's how the end of the year goes."]
その始まりは
二十数年前にさかのぼる｡
It began twenty-some years ago.
江戸へと飛来した
天人の船は 江戸城へ攻撃を開始｡
The Amanto ships arrived in
Edo and began their attack,
その圧倒的な武力を背景に➡
using overwhelming military force
to compel the opening of Edo.
高圧的な態度をもって
開国を強要した｡
度重なる不平等条約の締結｡
A number of unequal
treaties were signed.
幕府の弱腰の外交に業を煮やし➡
The samurai lost their patience with
the Bakufu's soft foreign policy
危機感を覚えた侍たちは
攘夷という思想のもとに集い➡
and sensing the crisis at hand,
they gathered under
the Anti-Foreign ideal.
戦いはしたが ただただ多くの者が
死んでいっただけだった｡
They fought,
but their actions only led to much death.
However, the war unexpectedly
reached a stalemate.
しかしその後 戦いは
大方の予想に反して➡
膠着状態へと陥った｡
技術力では 天と地ほどの
差があったにもかかわらず➡
The Amanto had an overwhelming
technological advantage,
攘夷志士たちは
優位とは言えないまでも➡
but the efforts of the Anti-Foreigner Faction
allowed them to at least put up a fight.
健闘したと言えるまでの
成果を出した｡
正面からの戦闘を避け➡
That was largely because they avoided direct
battles and adopted guerrilla warfare.
ｹﾞﾘﾗ戦に特化した
戦術をとったことは大きい｡
じゃが そのいちばんの理由は➡
But the main reason was
彼らが侍だったからじゃ｡
because they were samurai.
明らかに劣る武装でも
彼らは 恐れることなく戦った｡
Even if their weapons
were clearly inferior,
they fought without any fear.
The highly advanced Amanto were unable to
understand the desperation of the samurai.
高度な文明を持つ 天人たちは➡
一見 捨て鉢ともとれる
侍たちの思考を理解できなかった｡
Samurai...
侍…
天人たちは その存在に恐怖した｡
The Amanto feared their existence.
だが その結果
戦闘は長期化し 泥沼の戦へ｡
But that served to prolong the
war as it became a quagmire.
そうじゃ｡
That's right.
長きにわたる戦闘の日々
国賊の汚名まで着せられた➡
A very long period of war existed, during which the
Anti-Foreigner Faction were labeled traitors,
攘夷志士じゃったが
それでも 希望は生まれる｡
but there was still hope.
この頃から
一部の若者が頭角を現してきた｡
This was when a group of young people
began distinguishing themselves.
狂乱の貴公子 桂小太郎｡
The unstoppable noble, Kotaro Katsura.
鬼兵隊を率いた 高杉晋介｡
The leader of the Kiheitai,
Shinsuke Takasugi.
免許皆伝の剣術の使い手
坂本辰馬ら そうそうたる面々｡
A master swordsman,
Tatsuma Sakamoto.
An impressive bunch.
命を賭して戦う 彼らのその姿に
攘夷の気運は 再び 高まり➡
The Faction regained their morale as they
saw these men risk their lives in battle.
Soon, a large number of young men
had assembled around them.
彼らの周囲には
知らず知らずのうちに➡
多数の若者が集うことになった｡
表向きには… ですよね？
On the surface, correct?
How much do you know?
どこまで知っとる？
正確に言えば 何も…｡
Technically, I know nothing.
だが その存在は確認しています｡
But I have confirmed that he existed.
歴史の表舞台には
決して その姿を現さない反面➡
An enigma, who wielded
unparalleled influence
for a person who never appeared
in the pages of history.
これほどの影響力を持った者は➡
他にいないと言っていい
謎の存在…｡
Blazing across the battlefield in a flash
白き姿で戦場を駆け その一撃は➡
屈強なる天人をも
一太刀のもと 切り裂いた｡
of white as he cut down sturdy
Amanto with one swing.
味方からは
精神的支柱として 尊敬を集め➡
Admired by allies as a pillar of support
while instilling terror in his foes.
敵からは 畏怖の念を込め
白い悪魔と呼ばれた｡
He was known as the "White Devil."
白い悪魔…｡
The White Devil...?
Yes.
ああ… 他にも
いくつか 呼び名はあったがな｡
'Course, he was called by many names.
知ってるんですね やはり！
So you do know of him!
教えてください 彼のことを！
Please tell me about him!
What will you do with that knowledge?
それを知って どうする？
You should understand.
あなたにも わかるはずだ｡
As a journalist, I wish to know the truth!
私は
新聞記者として真実を知りたい！
わしが初めて ﾔﾂを見たのは
あのときじゃった｡
The first time I saw him was back then...
((くっ！ まさか こんなところで
待ち伏せに遭うとは!!
I didn't expect an ambush here!
早く撤退しなければ
被害は増えるばかりだ！
We must retreat immediately or
there will be more casualties!
Are you insane?
正気か？ 今 ここで ﾔﾂらに
背中をむけりゃ それこそ全滅だ｡
We'll be wiped out if we
turn our backs and run!
しかし！
万事休すか？
However!
Are we out of options?
ﾊﾞｶを言え！ ｵﾚたちには ﾔﾂがいる｡
ﾔﾂは 必ず来る！
Don't be foolish!
We still have him!
He will surely come!
ﾔﾂか…｡
Him, huh?
What was that?!
何ごとだ!?
３ ６ ７番艦 撃沈！
Ships 3, 6, and 7 have been shot down!
来たか！
He has come!
し… 白い悪魔か！))
Th-The White Devil...
(永井)そう ﾔﾂこそが 白い悪魔…｡
Yes, he was the White Devil...
ｶﾞﾝﾀﾞﾑじゃ！
Gundam!
って… おい！
｢ｶﾞﾝﾀﾞﾑじゃ！｣ じゃねえんだよ!!
Wait!
Gundam, my ass!
You've got the wrong show!
もう 番組が違ってんじゃねえか！
I-it's for the 30th anniversary!
[Note: 2009 is the 30th anniversary of Gundam.]
さ さ… 30周年記念じゃ｡
That doesn't matter!
関係ねえだろ！ これ ただ お前が
ｶﾞﾝﾀﾞﾑ 出したかっただけのﾎﾗ話？
Are you just making up a story so
you can talk about Gundam?
[Mobile Suit Gundam 30th Anniversary Special Extra #2]
I-It wasn't me!
わ… わしじゃない！
この番組のｽﾀｯﾌじゃ!!
It was the staff of this show!
That's even worse!
よけいに ﾀﾁが悪いわ！
(時報)
Kabukicho radio exercise #1.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]かぶき町 ﾗｼﾞｵ体操 第一…｡
Ready...
いってきま～す！
I'm off!
["Radio Exercises are Socials
for Boys and Girls"]
Okay, we're done.
はい じゃあ おしまい！
I'll stamp your card, so line up.
ﾊﾝｺ押すんで
皆さん こっちに並んでください｡
[Kagura]
神楽ちゃん すごいね｡
今んとこ 皆勤じゃん｡
That's impressive, Kagura-chan.
You have perfect attendance so far.
But if you keep barely showing up on time,
you'll miss out one of these days.
でも いつも
あんな ｷﾞﾘｷﾞﾘに滑り込んでたら➡
そのうち ﾊﾝｺ逃しちゃうぞ｡
Sleep deprivation really
hurts your beauty.
寝不足は美容の大敵ね｡
Women need every minute
of sleep they can get.
女は １分１秒でも多く
睡眠をとらなければいけないｱﾙ｡
I can see how you're able to walk around
in public with that haystack on your head.
さすが！ ﾔﾏﾝﾊﾞみたいな頭して
人前に出てくるだけ あるわ｡
But you're really amazing.
でも ﾎﾝﾄ 偉いよ｡
かぶき町の子供なんて➡
The kids in Kabukicho have become
know-it-alls and don't even bother coming.
みんな ｽﾚちゃって
こんな行事 相手にしないもの｡
来るのは 健康ｵﾀｸか
じいさん ばあさんだけ｡
We only get health freaks
and senior people.
You're the only kid who comes.
子供は 神楽ちゃんくらい…
あ！ もう一人いたか｡
Oh, there was one more.
That's Hisashi Hongo-kun.
あれ 本郷尚君｡
彼も今んとこ 皆勤だね｡
He also has perfect attendance so far.
なんでも 体が弱いとかで
健康のために➡
I heard that he's participating for health
reasons since he's not very strong.
参加してるらしいんだけど
偉いよ～ 彼は｡
He's a good kid.
He always shows up fifteen minutes
before the exercise begins.
体操開始 15分前には
必ず 来てるもの｡
ふ～ん… まぁ どうせ
今日までの命ｱﾙ｡
Well, that will come to an end today.
今日の金曜ﾛｰﾄﾞｼｮｰは ｢魔女宅｣ｱﾙ｡
Today's Friday night movie slot
is "Kiki's Delivery Service".
A kid could never ignore
Kiki and go to bed.
｢魔女宅｣をｽﾙｰして早寝するなんて
ｶﾞｷには不可能｡
Stay up all night to dreams of Kiki.
せいぜい ｷｷで妄想にふけり
夜更かしするがいいね！
ﾑﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
Kabukicho radio exercise #1.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]かぶき町 ﾗｼﾞｵ体操第一！
よ～い…｡
Ready...
Lift your arms up and stretch your back.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]腕を前から上に
大きく 背伸びの運動｡
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]１ ２ ３ ４！ ５ ６ ７ ８！
1, 2, 3, 4.
5, 6, 7, 8.
う～ん…
だいぶ少なくなってきたね｡
Less people are showing up.
やっぱり みんな お盆休みに
どこか行っちゃったのかな｡
I guess they all went on
vacation for Obon break.
Kagura-chan, are you going
anywhere during Obon?
神楽ちゃん
ん？
お盆は どっか行くの？
神楽ちゃん
目の下に ｸﾏできてるけど…｡
Kagura-chan?
You have bags under your eyes.
なんでもないね｡
ﾊﾟﾝ屋の旦那が最高だっただけｱﾙ｡
It's nothing.
It's just the baker's husband
being so awesome.
What baker's husband?
ﾊﾟﾝ屋の旦那って何？
ひょっとして 見た？
You watched it?
｢魔女宅｣見た？
夜更かししちゃった？
You watched Kiki?
You stayed up late then?
Lift your arms up and stretch your back.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]腕を前から上に
大きく 背伸びの運動｡
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]１ ２ ３ ４！
1, 2, 3, 4.
3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
Bend your knees with your arms at your side and
motion like a ca[beep]ret girl pouring liquor.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]ﾋｻﾞを前から倒し 腕を横に
お酒を注ぐｷｬ…嬢の運動｡
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]１ ２ ３ ４！
1, 2, 3, 4.
Now drop to the ground like a
sxxp girl greeting a customer.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]体を地に伏せ
ｿｰ…嬢のお迎えの運動｡
5, 6, 7, 8.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]いらっしゃいませ～｡
Welcome.
Now spread your legs like a str[beep]er.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]足を大きく開き
ｽﾄﾘｯ…嬢の運動｡
Then we'll see you again tomorrow.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]それじゃあ また明日｡
さようなら｡
["Visiting my family. Please stamp
the card yourselves." - Tanaka]
U-Uh...
(尚)あ… あの…｡
ん？
ﾊﾝｺ…｡ おじさん
今日 来ないって聞いて…｡
The stamp...
I heard that he wasn't coming
today, so I brought one.
ﾎﾞｸ 持ってきたんだけど…
よかったら 押そうか？
If you'd like, I could stamp yours.
You aren't going anywhere
for summer vacation?
(神楽)お前は 夏休み
どこも行かないｱﾙか？
Is your family also poor?
ひょっとして お前んちも
金がないｱﾙか？
お金っていうか…
ﾎﾞｸ 体が弱くて➡
It's not so much money as...
I have health problems so I have to
visit the hospital on a regular basis.
頻繁に 病院に
顔出さなきゃいけないから…｡
I can't take any extended trips.
あんまり遠出はできなくて…｡
そっか｡ 金はあっても
体が いうこときかないｱﾙか｡
I see.
You have the money, but your body
won't do what you want it to.
Nothing works out in this world.
世の中 うまくいかないｱﾙな｡
My body's perfectly fine,
but I have no money.
私は 体はﾋﾟﾝﾋﾟﾝだけど
金はﾋﾟｰﾋﾟｰね｡
それが いちばんだよ｡
ﾎﾞｸなんて こんな体だから➡
It's better that way.
With my health problems,
I can't do anything very long.
いつも
なんでも長続きしなくて…｡
I don't even get to go to the
temple school as much.
寺子屋にも ﾛｸに通えてないし…｡
だから この夏 これだけは
最後までやりきろうと思って｡
That's why I wanted to see this
through to the end of summer.
せっかく この世に生まれたのに➡
It would be sad if I wasn't able to accomplish
anything after being born into this world.
なんにも やり遂げないで
終わっちゃうのは寂しいし…｡
なんでもいいんだ｡ ひとつでも
何かをやり遂げたくて…｡
Anything will do.
I just wanted to see
something to the end.
That's pretty ominous.
不吉なこと 言うｱﾙな｡
You sound like you're about to die.
まるで もうすぐ
死んじゃうみたいｱﾙ｡
S-Sorry...
ごめん… ﾎﾞｸの悪いｸｾで
なんでも悲観的に考えちゃうんだ｡
I have a bad habit of being
pessimistic about everything.
でも 神楽ちゃんがいてくれて
よかった｡
But I'm glad that you're here.
ひとりじゃ寂しいし…｡
I would have been lonely all by myself.
神楽ちゃん 明日も来るよね？
Kagura-chan, will you come
again tomorrow?
当たり前ｱﾙ！
私は いったん行くと決めたら➡
Of course.
Once I've made up my mind, I'll come
if it's raining cats or dogs or spears.
雨が降っても槍が降っても行くね｡
お前も男だったら➡
If you're a man, stop whining and
finish what you set out to do.
弱気なことばっか言ってないで
ﾊﾞｽｰﾝと やることやり通すｱﾙ｡
体 引きずってでも来いよ｡
You'd better come, even if you
have to drag yourself here.
I can't be motivated if I don't
have any competition.
私も張り合うﾔﾂがいないと
やりがいがないね｡
う… うん｡
ありがとう 神楽ちゃん｡
Y-Yeah.
Thanks, Kagura-chan.
一緒に がんばろうね｡
Let's do our best together.
おう！
Yeah!
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]かぶき町
ﾗｼﾞｵ体操 第二！ よ～い！
Kabukicho radio exercise #2.
Ready...
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]両足跳びで
軽く全身を揺する運動から｡
Relax your entire body while hopping.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]１ ２ ３ ４…｡
1, 2, 3, 4.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]右手を宙に置いて
酔っぱらいの運動｡
Stick your right hand in the air
while hurling like a drunk.
5, 6, 7, 8.
Can't you tell that I have a hangover?
二日酔いだってのが
わかんねえのか… うっ…｡
さすが銀ちゃんｱﾙ！ 超本格的ね！
That's our Gin-chan!
He's like the real thing!
[Sakata]
Spread your arms and flex like a gorilla.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]両腕を大きく開き
力こぶ！ ｺﾞﾘﾗの運動｡
さすが姉御ｱﾙ！ ｺﾞﾘﾗそっくりね！
That's our boss lady!
Looks just like a gorilla!
[Shimura]
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]手足を その場で大きく振り
攘夷浪士の運動！
Wave your arms and legs while sprinting
like an Anti-Foreigner Faction man.
待て!!
さすが ﾂﾞﾗｱﾙ！
Wait!
That's our Zura!
Catch him already!
さっさと捕まれよ ﾊﾞｶ！
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない 桂だ!!
It's Katsura, not Zura!
[Katsura]
Get on all fours like a [beep]
waiting to be punished.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]四つん這いになり
お仕置きを待つ …ﾌﾞﾀの運動｡
(さっちゃん)ぶちなさいよ！
ああ 好きなだけ ぶちなさいよ！
Smack me!
Smack me all you want!
[Sarutobi]
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]手足を放り ﾌﾟﾗｲﾄﾞも放る
無職の運動！
Lie flat on your back on the ground,
like a man without a job.
(長谷川)運動じゃねえじゃん！
なんにもしてねえじゃん！
This isn't exercise!
I'm not doing anything here!
[Hasegawa]
神楽ちゃん 誰かと一緒に
何かをやり遂げるって➡
Kagura-chan, I never knew how fun it was to
accomplish something with someone else.
こんなに楽しかったんだね｡
What are you saying all of a sudden?
何言いだすね 急に｡
ﾎﾞｸ… 今まで
自分が何もできないの➡
I always blamed my inability to do anything
on my illness, my poor health.
全部 病気のせいに…
体のせいにしてきた｡
もっと普通の体だったら…
もっと ﾎﾞｸが元気だったらって➡
If only I had a normal body...
If only I was healthy...
人を羨んできた｡
I was being jealous of other people for it.
But that wasn't what I needed.
でも ﾎﾞｸに必要なのは
そんなんじゃなかったんだね｡
ﾎﾞｸ ﾗｼﾞｵ体操に参加してよかった｡
I'm glad I joined in these radio exercises.
つらいことも
一緒にいたら楽しくなる｡
I learned that the hard things can
be fun when you're with others...
神楽ちゃんみたいな友達に
会えたんだもの｡
It's all because I made a friend like you.
ｱ… ｱﾎｱﾙか｡ 何を浮かれてるね｡
A-Are you stupid?
Why are you so happy?
まだ ﾊﾝｺは全部埋まってないね｡
Your card hasn't been
completely stamped yet!
帰って 家の人に
ただいまって言うまでが遠足｡
A field trip isn't over until you've made
it home and greeted your parents!
最後のﾊﾝｺもらって 帰宅して
二度寝するまでが ﾗｼﾞｵ体操ね！
Radio exercises aren't over until you've gotten
your last stamp and gone home to take a nap!
ﾗｽﾄを走りきるまで
気 抜くなよ｡ ｼｬﾊﾞ蔵が！
Don't relax until you've gotten through
the last spurt, goody two-shoes!
(尚)うん｡
Right!
(神楽)中止!?
Canceled?!
どういうことｱﾙか？
そんなの 聞いてないね！
What do you mean?
I didn't hear anything about that!
聞いてるも聞いてないも
こんな雨ん中で➡
What is there to hear?
What kind of fool would
go exercise in this rain?
体操するﾊﾞｶが どこにいるよ？
ここにいるね！
This fool right here!
こんなもんで
休むわけにはいかないｱﾙ!!
A little rain won't be enough to stop me!
The radio exercise itself is canceled.
ﾗｼﾞｵ体操自体が休みなの｡
Kids don't do radio exercises
when it rains,
女の子の日に 女子が
水泳の授業出られねえみてぇに➡
雨の日に 子供は
ﾗｼﾞｵ体操できねえの｡
just as girls don't participate in swimming
class when it's that time of the month.
で… でも せっかく
ここまで ﾊﾝｺ…｡
B-But after I got all these stamped...
んなもん あとで
ｵﾚが押してやるよ｡
I'll stamp it for you later.
雨んときは いいの｡
不戦勝みたいなもんなの｡
Doesn't count if it's raining.
Like an unearned win.
そういう問題じゃないね！
私たちは やりきりたいだけｱﾙ！
That's not the issue here!
We want to see this through!
やりたいっつっても➡
Doesn't change the fact
that it's been canceled.
やってねえもんは
しゃあねえだろ｡
いい機会じゃねえか｡
たまには休むのも｡
This is a good opportunity for you to rest.
Isn't that kid unhealthy?
あのｶﾞｷも体 よえぇんだろう？
あまり ﾑﾁｬさせんなよ｡
Don't push him too hard.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]かぶき町
ﾗｼﾞｵ体操 第一 よ～い！
Kabukicho radio exercise #1.
Ready...
((神楽:倒れたって… どうして？
He collapsed?!
Why?!
こないだまで
あんな元気だったのに…｡
He was fine just the other day...
He was exercising with me!
一緒に体操してたのに…｡
ｳﾁの子 もう長くないって
お医者様に言われてたの｡
Our son doesn't have long to live...
That's what the doctor said.
あの子には隠してたんだけど
たぶん気づいていたんでしょうね｡
Though we never told him.
He must have realized...
He suddenly said that he wanted
to accomplish something.
急に何かしたい なんて
言い出して…｡
The doctor said to have him rest,
お医者様には 安静にするよう
言われてたんだけど➡
どうしても体操やらしてくれって
聞かなくて…｡
but he kept begging us
to let him go exercise.
でも まさか➡
But I never thought that he would
have gone out in that rain...
あの雨の中でまで…｡
He said he'll go even if it's raining
cats or dogs or spears.
雨が降っても 槍が降っても
やりとげる｡
That was the promise he
made with his first friend.
そう初めての友達と
約束したんだ って…｡
私 約束 破ったｱﾙ｡
I broke our promise...
雨降っても 槍降っても
必ず行くって そう約束したのに➡
I said I would come if it was raining
cats or dogs or spears.
I promised...
ごめん 私があんなこと…｡
Sorry... If I hadn't said that...
いいんだ｡ 約束なんかしなくても｡
It's okay.
I would have gone, even
if you hadn't promised.
ﾎﾞｸ 行ってたよ｡
雨なんかに ﾎﾞｸらの今までの努力が
ｼﾞｬﾏされるの 悔しいだろ？
It would be frustrating for rain to get in the
way of everything we've accomplished.
だけど やっぱりﾀﾞﾒだったみたい｡
But I guess it was no good.
ひとりで体操しても
やっぱり つまらなかった｡
It was no fun exercising by myself.
神楽ちゃんがいないと
楽しくなかった…｡
It wasn't any fun without Kagura-chan.
ごめんね 手伝ってくれたのに
ﾎﾞｸ やっぱり最後までﾀﾞﾒみたい｡
Sorry, you helped me this far.
But it looks like I won't be able to
see this through to the end.
ﾀﾞﾒなんかじゃないｱﾙ｡
That's not true.
You can't give up yet.
まだ あきらめちゃﾀﾞﾒね｡
I'll keep exercising and getting
stamps until you come back.
お前が戻ってくるまで
体操してﾊﾝｺ押しとくね｡
Did you know?
知ってるｱﾙか？
You can get a stamp on a rainy day
because it's like an unearned win.
雨の日は 不戦勝扱いで
ﾊﾝｺつけてもいいんだよ｡
だから… だから戻ってくるｱﾙ｡
So...
So come back.
また一緒に体操するｱﾙ｡
We can exercise together again.
It won't stop raining until you come back.
お前が戻ってくるまで
雨 やまないからな｡
待ってるｱﾙ… ずっと))
I'll be waiting...
The whole time...
かぶき町 ﾗｼﾞｵ体操 第一！
Kabukicho radio exercise #1!
Ready!
よ～い！
Hey, I said ready.
ほら 用意って言ったんだ｡
立て！ ﾊﾝｺやんねえぞ！
Stand.
Or I won't stamp you.
銀ちゃん…｡
まずは 腕を前から上に➡
Gin-chan...
First, lift your arms up
and stretch your back!
大きく背伸びをする運動！
はい！
１ ２ ３ ４！ ５ ６ ７ ８！
Yes!
1, 2, 3, 4!
5, 6, 7, 8!
２ ２ ３ ４！ ５ ６ ７ ８！
1, 2, 3, 4!
5, 6, 7, 8!
１ ２ ３ ４！ ５ ６ ７ ８！
1, 2, 3, 4!
２ ２ ３…｡
5, 6, 7, 8!
1, 2, 3...
Okay! Now line up!
はい じゃあ 並べ！
横入りすんじゃねえぞ 順番な！
No cutting!
Hey, kid. What do you
think you're doing?
おい ﾃﾒｴ！ ｶﾞｷ 何やってんだ！
ﾊﾝｺの代わりに
焼印押してやろうか!?
Want me to brand you
instead of a stamp?
(神楽)雨 やんだｱﾙ｡
It stopped raining...
[Preview]
Hey, hold on.
We're just here to catch Hoichi,
the boss of Kabukicho stray cats, right?
So why?
So WHY?!
Why do I look like THIS?!
The next episode...
"When Looking for Something,
Try Using its Perspective."
[We'd like to believe that pure, young children
who believe in Santa Claus watch this anime.]
[Next episode, the Kabukicho Stray Cat arc begins.
Gin-san is cursed and turned into a cat!?]
[See you next time.]